A Guide to the Papers of Virginius Dabney
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7690-ai
Virginius Dabney Papers 1927-1984
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7690-ai
65 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1986 December 22
Container List
- Series I: Manuscripts
  - The Jefferson Scandals: A Rebuttal, 1981; TMs
  - The Last Review The Confederate Reunion, Richmond, 1932, [ca. 1984]; TMs
  - The Last Review The Confederate Reunion, Richmond, 1932 (Final Version), 1984; TMs
- Series II: Articles
  - The Myth of the Ride of Paul Revere, 1927
  - "Campaign Literature" in The Virginia Quarterly Review, 1928 Oct
  - "On the Labor Front" in The New Republic, 1938 Apr 27
  - "Medicine in a Changing World" in The American Journal of Pharmaceutical Education, 1939 Jul
  - "Ideals of American Democracy" in The Commonwealth, 1940 Sep
  - "The South Looks Abroad" in Foreign Affairs, 1940 Oct
  - "The Honor System's First Hundred Years" in The University of Virginia Alumni News, 1942 May
  - "What Americans Think About Post-War Reconstruction in the South" in Foreign Policy Reports, 1942 Oct 1
  - "The Poll Tax Stirs Revolt" in National Municipal Review, 1942 Oct
  - "An Approach to Virginia" in Saturday Review, 1943 Jan 23
  - "News, Propaganda and the War" in The Madison Quarterly, 1943 Mar
  - "Interracial Adjustment in the South" in The Economist, 1943 Jul 31
  - "The Dynamic New South" in The New York Times Magazine, 1943 Oct 17
  - "The South and the World" in The Economist, 1943 Nov 20
  - "Newspapers and the Negro" in The Quill, 1943 Nov-Dec
  - "Let's Get Out of the Bag" in Washington News Digest, 1945 Jul
  - "Is the South That Bad?" in Pace, 1946 Jun 19
  - "Ochs of the Times" in The American Mercury, 1946 Aug
  - "The Two-Party System Goes South" in New York Herald Tribune This Week Magazine, 1954 Jan 3
  - "An American in England Munich and McCarthy" in The Manchester Guardian, 1954 Nov 5
  - "Plain Talk Across the Sea" in New York Herald Tribune This Week Magazine, 1954 Nov 14
  - "If the South Had Won the War" in American Mercury, 1956 Feb
  - "A Frank Talk to North and South About Intergration" in U.S. News and World Report, 1957 Mar 15
  - "School Integration" in Vital Speeches of the Day, 1957 Apr l
  - "Journalism" in A Guide to Career Opportunities, 1958 Feb
  - "Virginia's Peaceable, Honorable Stand" in Life, 1958 Sep 22
  - Review of Separate and Unequal: Public School Campaigns and Racism in the Southern Seaboard States, 1901-1915 in The Virginia Magazine, 1959 Jan
  - "Next in the South's Schools: Limited Integration" in U.S. News and World Report, 1960 Jan 18
  - "How the World Sees the United States" in Saturday Review, 1961 Sep 23
  - "What is the New Germany?" in Saturday Review, 1963 Mar 9
  - "New Ways to Permanent Files" in Saturday Review, 1964 May 9
  - "The Good Southern Universities" in Harper's, 1965 Mar
  - "The Pace is Important" in The Virginia Quarterly Review, 1965 Spring
  - "From Cuckoo Tavern to Monticello" in The Iron Worker, 1966 Summer
  - "Cheating in the Classroom Can Be Stopped" in Pageant, 1966 Dec
  - "The Mystery of the Hamilton-Burr Duel" in New York, 1976 Mar 29
  - "Liberty and Slavery: The Anomaly of Colonial Virginia" in The Virginia Quarterly Review, 1976 Spring
  - "I'm Distraught and Unhappy Over What I See" in The American Society of Newspaper Editors Bulletin w/ related correspondence, 1982-1983